Tate Peñaranda

Software Engineer



Summary

Hi! I'm Tate, human being. A Software Engineer who focus on quality, testeable, maintanable and scalable code but, on the other hand, a Developer who understands that, from the business perspective, the most important thing is delivered code and a product that just works.

During last twenty years I have played with lots of different technologies, starting with ASM on RISC architectures and today, having fun with Node, React, AWS, UX and looking to be as close as possible to product and end user.

Nice to meet you.

Let's build something amazing!

The technologies I've been using during the latest months includes:

- Javascript, Node, React, Redux, Auth0, ES6, Tailwind, Webpack, Jest, AWS Rekognition, AWS S3, AWS Lambda
- MongoDB, MySQL, Redis, PM2, Express, Semantic UI, Postmark, Bugsnag, DigitalOcean, Linux, TDD, Git, Scrum, Agile.

Experience

Apr 2020 **Technical Lead**, *Mission*, Remote

Present Projects:

- Mission [formerly GSquad] (Montréal, Quebec, Canada) Apr 2020 Present: Mission is the first private global market network for software engineers looking for a better way to work.
 - Role: Technical Lead.
 - Technologies: React, Node, AWS.

Oct 2021 CTO, Foto Escurra, On-site

Present Projects:

- Foto Escurra (Villa La Angostura, Neuquén, Argentina) Oct 2021 Present: Foto Escurra is an on-line photo store for outdoors competitions where participants use bib numbers OCR and facial recognition in order to find and buy photos.
 - Role: CTO, Architect and Developer, the do-it-all guy.
 - Technologies: React, Node, Express, AWS Rekognition, AWS Lambda, AWS S3.

Jun 2020 **Team Lead**, *TradeHelm Inc.*, Remote

Mar 2022 Projects:

- RepTrak (Boston, MA, USA) Jun 2020 Mar 2022: The RepTrak Company helps business leaders understand how their company is perceived so they can maximize business outcomes.
 - Role: FE Team Lead.
 - Responsibilities: App FE and company React components internal repository.
 - Technologies: React, Docker, Auth0, Tailwind, Symfony.

Jun 2020 Part-time Developer, Ranker, Remote

Apr 2021 Projects:

- Ranker (Los Angeles, CA, USA) Jun 2020 Present: Ranker offers crowdsourced polls and lists across a variety of topics, including rankings of food, drinks, and celebrities.
 - Role: FE Developer.
 - Technologies: React, CSS.

Feb 2018 **Software Engineer**, *Blockinit LLC*, Remote

Jun 2020 Projects:

 FixMyCar (Michigan, MI, USA) Mar 2020 - Jun 2020: FixMyCar is a trusted mobile auto repair service dedicated to fixing your car repair problems with total convenience and 100% transparency.

This project was a classic RoR app using Slim templates looking to move one step forward, improve quality and move on with ReactJS. So that was what I did, start a new React app from scratch and integrate with the current Rails BE (plus a few new endpoints). Results? A brand new site that looks like a mobile app on phone due to responsive design, happy users and happy developers playing with a brand new FE codebase that's is so easy to maintain. Oh, and in just 3 months.

- Role: FE Lead.
- Responsibilities: Redesign and refactor the FE in order to switch from SSR to a ReactJS
 / RoR architecture.
- Technologies: React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, API Restful, Swagger.
- The Quartz Clinic (New Port Beach, CA, USA) Sep 2019 Feb 2020: The Quartz Clinic aims to discover the root cause of patient symptoms, make a nutrition plan and get real results with a virtual functional nutritionist at your fingertips.

These kinds of projects are my favorites, I see them as an opportunity to do what I love and have an impact on people's quality of life. I built this from scratch, and since we did focus on speed an low cost, we did choices like Auth0 in order to speed up BE and Mobile development. No need to reinvent the wheel, we're using Google Calendar API to manage Appointments and Zoom API to create conference links, live chat is an external service, Square handles the payments and the BE are a few endpoints handled by Larevel 6. Fast, easy, light and smooth, but... putting everything togheter ends on happy Nutritionists and happy Patients.

- Role: Architect, Full Stack and Mobile Developer.
- Responsibilities: Entire IT stack.
- Technologies: Laravel 6, VueJS, React Native, Redux, Forge, Auth0, Square, Google Calendar API, Postmark, PHPUnit.

• Redeeem (Los Angeles, CA, USA) Feb 2018 - Jul 2019: Redeeem is #1 most trusted source of discounted Amazon Gift Cards. At Redeeem each user has a Bitcoin wallet and is able to buy/sell gift cards.

I had the chance to plan, design and write the very first line of code for the app. Being the only dev on a low budget project forced me to handle FE, BE, infrastructure and blockchain integration. It was my first interaction with bitcoin node but dev process was smooth and fast, after a few weeks MVP was live, including users wallets, transactions and external integrations (Shopify, Workato, Postmark).

- Role: PHP Architect.
- Responsibilities: API endpoints, BCoin node, FE, BE, Design, Architecture, Documentation, Branching Strategies, Deploys and Services Integrations.
- Technologies: Laravel 5, VueJS, BCoin, Bitcoin Wallets, Heroku, Workato, Amazon Turk, Figure Eight (Crowdflower), Composer, Fractal.
- Lune (San Mateo, CA, USA) Jun 2018 Jun 2019: Lune is on a mission to bring the breakthrough power of personalized nutrition within everyone's reach. It combines home-to-lab testing with digital nutrition coaching to bring health transformations.

Lune was a sweet challenge for our small team (2 BE, 1 FE, 1 Mobile, 1 QA). On this project I found how flexible I can be as a dev, since at the very beginning I was in charge of the FE, later I switched to BE and finally I was the one handling the mobile app. We did it really well, deploying an MVP in months and final product after a year, as expected.

- Role: Full Stack and Mobile Developer.
- Responsibilities: FE, BE, Mobile, Services integrations.
- Technologies: Laravel 5, VueJS, React Native, Swagger, API, Forge, AWS, Fractal, Shipbob, Typeform.

Apr 2016 **Senior Software Developer**, *Deviget LLC*, Remote

Feb 2018 Projects:

- Harvey (Santa Monica, CA, USA, Apr 2017 Feb 2018): Harvey is the leading telehealth provider of integrative medicine that emphasizes prevention, self-healing and sciencebased natural therapies to help patients suffering from acute and chronic health conditions.
 - Role: PHP Developer.
 - Responsibilities: New features, API endpoints to feed FE and mobile apps, services integrations, DB schema/performance.
 - Technologies: Laravel 5, AWS, Bugsnag, Slack, Github, IronMQ, Jira, VueJS, Elastic-search, Scout, PHPUnit, Dusk. Travis CI.
- DeringHall (New York, NY, USA, Feb 2017 Apr 2017): Dering Hall is a curated shopping resource for discerning consumers and trade providing insider access to thousands of luxury design products and services.
 - Role: Ruby Developer.
 - Responsibilities: Maintenance to web application, SEO.
 - Technologies: Rails 5, MySQL, Elasticsearch, jQuery, Heroku.

- HomeHero (Santa Monica, CA, USA, Apr 2016 Dec 2016): HomeHero is a senior home care marketplace. His mission is to become the most recognizable brand in the world associated with senior home care.
 - Role: PHP Developer.
 - Responsibilities: BE for internal portal used by company agents. This tool, was in charge of tasks like scheduling and billing of Caregivers shifts.
 - Technologies: Laravel 5, AWS, Stripe, Bugsnag, Slack, Github, IronMQ, Jira, VueJS.

Aug 2011 **Senior Software Developer**, *Velocity Partners*, Rosario, Argentina Mar 2016 Projects:

- G2 Web Services (Bellevue, WA, USA, Oct 2011 Jan 2015): Its main role is to audit
 and monitor online e-commerce transactions and their merchants in order to avoid
 counterfeits, data robbery, illegal transactions, content violations, etc.
 - Role: Ruby SDET, Lead PHP Dev.
 - Responsibilities: Dev lead for a remote MNT team (4 Devs, 1 QA) located at Hyderabad (India). I joined this project as SDET and finally I ended up as PHP Dev Lead, also I was in charge of the project hand-off at Bellevue, after Velocity and G2 business finished
 - Technologies: Ruby (RoR 3, RubyCAS-Server, RSpec, Capybara, Sinatra, Grape) PHP (Zend Framework), PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, ElasticSearch, Java and MyBatis ORM.
- Software Advice (Austin, TX, USA, Feb 2015 Aug 2015): Software Advice is a trusted resource for software buyers. It provides detailed reviews and research on thousands of software applications.
 - Role: PHP Developer.
 - Responsibilities: I had to provide a reliable, fast, maintainable and easy to use PHP library, as a Composer package, for pulling data and generate statistic about products, sellers phone calls and sales.
 - Technologies: PHP, MySQL, Sphinx, CSS3, HTML, SendGrid, Sonar, Jenkins, React, Composer
- Kinnser (Austin, TX, USA, Aug 2015 Mar 2016): Kinnser Software was founded in 2003 to create innovative Web-based solutions that deliver clinical and business results for the home health industry.
 - Role: ColdFusion Developer.
 - Responsibilities: MNT for Kinnser web/mobile application.
 - Technologies: ColdFusion, SQL Server, AngularJS, Less.

Nov 2008 **IT Infrastructure Architect**, *Eudoro Díaz Public Library*, Rosario, Argentina Jun 2012 https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biblioteca_Pedagógica_Eudoro_Díaz

- Linux and WS server administration. Services, Databases and Internet spread.
- o OpenVPN server, Apache, MySQL and DNS cache management
- Captive Wi-Fi portal.
- Open source environment migration.
- Scripting in Bash, Perl and Python.
- Joomla implementation.

Jan 2009 IT Engineer, Eductrade SA, Quito, Ecuador

Sep 2009 Improving the quality of popular education and social community. Installation and updates of computer classrooms. Assembly, installation and pointing of satellite dishes. Satelite link creation. Thin clients installation and configuration. WI-FI LAN creation and configuration. Application server installation and configuration. Communications server installation and configuration. Satellite modem installation and configuration Technologies: Linux (Debian), MS Windows 2008 Server, Thin clients, Satellite Communications, 3G, Structures cabling, Ms VBScript, Hughes HN7000S

Publications

April 20 Proofreader for "Laravel: Up and Running" 2nd edition, Author: Matt Stauffer,

2019 Publisher: O'Reilly, ISBN: 9781492041214

January 3 Fermentation temperature controller unit for home brewing using 16F648A,

2008 Revista MASH - Ciencia Cervecera, https://homebrewing.tpenaranda.com ASM coding for a well know RISC architecture, now deprecated.

Certifications

Scrum Master, Scrum Alliance July 2015, Certificant ID: 000435676 Certification Expires: 08 July 2017

Education

BEng Instituto Politécnico Superior General San Martín, Rosario, Argentina. 1997–2001

Languages

Spanish Mother tongue

English Advanced

Italian Intermediate